=His Chosen Favor=
=مفضلته المختارة=
(I opened a window on Noble Consort's head)
(فتحت نافذة على رأس القرينة النبيلة)
=Episode 4=
=الحلقة 4=
If you want me to spare her,
إذا كنت تريدني أن أعفو عنها،
then make Lu Zhen'er walk barefoot across this path,
ثم اجعل لو تشن إر تمشي حافية القدمين عبر هذا الطريق،
and I'll grant her one more day
وسأمنحها يوماً آخر
to uncover the murderer.
لكشف القاتل.
(If I walk this,)
(إذا مشيت هذا الطريق،)
(will I lose a limb?)
(هل سأفقد أحد أطرافي؟)
Too scared now?
هل أنت خائف الآن؟
I'll walk.
سأمشي.
I'll walk for her.
سأسير من أجلها.
Xiao Wenjing, these are burning coals!
شياو وينجينغ، هذه جمر مشتعل!
♪Spring comes late after the snow♪
♪يأتي الربيع متأخراً بعد الثلج♪
Mother,
الأم،
if I walk across,
إذا عبرت،
grant her a day to find the murderer,
امنحها يوماً واحداً للعثور على القاتل،
Have you gone mad?
هل جننت؟
♪Turning around, I lost you♪
♪استدرت، ففقدتك♪
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
♪يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي♪
Xiao Wenjing!
شياو ون جينغ!
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
♪تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف♪
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
♪ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح♪
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
♪الشوق ينسج في شبكة♪
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
♪لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر♪
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى نظرتك♪
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
♪الزمن، يترك وراءه الكثير من الماضي♪
(Xiao Wenjing.)
(شياو ون جينغ.)
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
♪فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا♪
♪Will I kiss your face♪
♪هل سأقبل وجهك؟♪
Mad! Just like your father!
مجنون! تماماً مثل والدك!
Both driven insane by this woman!
كلاهما أصيبا بالجنون بسبب هذه المرأة!
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
♪يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي♪
♪Our reunion veiled by moonlight♪
♪لقاءنا محجوب بضوء القمر♪
♪Grant me indifference or tenderness♪
♪امنحني اللامبالاة أو الحنان♪
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
♪تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف♪
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
♪ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح♪
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
♪الشوق ينسج في شبكة♪
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
♪لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر♪
Xiao Wenjing, are you alright?
شياو وينجينغ، هل أنت بخير؟
Mother, I've completed the walk.
أمي، لقد أكملت المشي.
♪Will I kiss your face♪
♪هل سأقبل وجهك؟♪
♪Never forgotten, hope you've been well♪
لن ننساك أبدًا، أتمنى أن تكون بخير
You better not be deceiving me.
من الأفضل ألا تخدعني.
I'm not deceiving you.
أنا لا أخدعك.
I didn't kill Consort Xi.
لم أقتل كونسورت شي.
So last night,
إذن، الليلة الماضية،
what exactly happened?
ما الذي حدث بالضبط؟
Consort Xi summoned me to beat me.
استدعتني المحظية شي لضربي.
I wouldn't stand there stupidly,
لن أقف هناك بغباء،
so I ran.
لذلك ركضت.
As for what happened later,
أما بالنسبة لما حدث لاحقاً،
my memory is unclear.
ذاكرتي غير واضحة.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
you killed her?
هل قتلتها؟
No way.
مستحيل.
I don't kill you now,
لن أقتلك الآن،
but next time might be different.
لكن ربما يكون الوضع مختلفاً في المرة القادمة.
If you push me further,
إذا ضغطت عليّ أكثر من ذلك،
I'll do anything.
سأفعل أي شيء.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
She is terrifying!
إنها مرعبة!
Of course, I wanted to kill her!
بالطبع، أردت قتلها!
But given our upbringing,
لكن بالنظر إلى تربيتنا،
I'll never commit murder.
لن أرتكب جريمة قتل أبداً.
I'll know once I investigate.
سأعرف ذلك بمجرد أن أتحقق من الأمر.
So confident?
واثق جدًا؟
Of course!
بالطبع!
Time-traveler's theorem!
نظرية المسافر عبر الزمن!
Once I investigate,
بمجرد أن أتحقق من الأمر،
it definitely won't be me.
بالتأكيد لن أكون أنا.
I was knocked unconscious!
لقد فقدت الوعي!
The one who knocked me out
الشخص الذي أغمى علي
is the murderer.
هو القاتل.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Where to?
إلى أين؟
Go to Consort Xi's maid.
اذهب إلى خادمة المحظية شي.
Ask her and we'll know.
اسألوها وسنعرف.
Let's go!
دعنا نذهب!
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
you...
أنت...
(Yanyu, Consort Xi's maid) Don't kill me!
(يانيو، خادمة المحظية شي) لا تقتلني!
She seems completely mad.
تبدو مجنونة تماماً.
Try torturing her.
حاول تعذيبها.
Forced confession?
اعتراف قسري؟
Don't.
لا.
Let me try first.
دعني أجرب أولاً.
Yanyu,
لك،
you were there that night.
كنتَ هناك في تلك الليلة.
Can you tell me
هل يمكن أن تخبرني
what happened
ماذا حدث؟
after I left?
بعد أن غادرت؟
Don't kill me!
لا تقتلني!
Help!
يساعد!
Apply torture.
مارس التعذيب.
Stop interfering.
توقف عن التدخل.
Stop investigating.
توقف عن التحقيق.
She's insane. We can't go on.
إنها مجنونة. لا يمكننا الاستمرار.
Stop mentioning torture.
توقفوا عن ذكر التعذيب.
Forced confessions are forbidden under my watch.
الاعترافات القسرية ممنوعة في عهدي.
I'll try another way.
سأجرب طريقة أخرى.
Your Highness, you just came in time.
يا صاحب السمو، لقد وصلتم في الوقت المناسب تماماً.
The imperial physicians just finished stitching the body.
انتهى الأطباء الإمبراطوريون للتو من خياطة الجثة.
Had you come earlier,
لو كنت قد أتيت في وقت سابق،
you may be too scared to look.
ربما تكون خائفًا جدًا من النظر.
Your Highness, don't.
يا صاحب السمو، لا تفعل.
What's inside?
ماذا يوجد بالداخل؟
Some of her bones were shattered.
تحطمت بعض عظامها.
The physicians couldn't fix it, so they stuffed cotton inside
لم يتمكن الأطباء من إصلاحها، فقاموا بحشو القطن في الداخل.
to make it appear presentable.
لجعلها تبدو لائقة.
This is
هذا هو
mercury.
الزئبق.
This is mercury.
هذا هو الزئبق.
Make an incision here
قم بعمل شق هنا
and pour mercury in.
ثم صب الزئبق فيه.
Then I'll get a complete human skin.
ثم سأحصل على جلد بشري كامل.
Your Highness, would you like to give it a try?
صاحب السمو، هل ترغب في تجربته؟
Impossible!
مستحيل!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
No way.
مستحيل.
Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحية طيبة، صاحب السمو.
- Greetings, Your Highness. - Both of you, leave.
- تحية طيبة يا صاحب السمو. - انصرفا أنتما الاثنان.
- Yes.
- نعم.
(Why is he here again?)
(لماذا هو هنا مرة أخرى؟)
Aren't you afraid?
ألا تخاف؟
Somewhat.
إلى حد ما.
If there's nothing else,
إذا لم يكن هناك شيء آخر،
I shall take my leave.
سأغادر الآن.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Don't you recognize me?
ألا تعرفني؟
I'm His Majesty's consorts.
أنا قرينة جلالة الملك.
Our relationship is above reproach.
علاقتنا لا تشوبها شائبة.
Seems you've embraced this new identity.
يبدو أنك قد تقبلت هذه الهوية الجديدة.
(Did the original owner have a relationship with him?)
(هل كانت تربط المالك الأصلي علاقة به؟)
(If I deny it now,)
(إذا أنكرت ذلك الآن،)
(would it undermine my character?)
(هل سيؤثر ذلك سلباً على شخصيتي؟)
(Before I get the full picture,)
(قبل أن تتضح لي الصورة كاملة،)
(I shall placate him.)
(سأسترضيه.)
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I have no choice but to obey.
ليس لدي خيار سوى الطاعة.
I am merely a powerless consort,
أنا مجرد قرينة عاجزة،
a woman who can't even harm a fly.
امرأة لا تستطيع حتى إيذاء ذبابة.
Yes, as a woman,
نعم، بصفتي امرأة،
what could you do against imperial power?
ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل في مواجهة القوة الإمبريالية؟
If that's all,
إذا كان هذا كل شيء،
I'll take my leave.
سأغادر الآن.
Wait.
انتظر.
I'm quite curious about something.
أشعر بفضول شديد حيال أمر ما.
What?
ماذا؟
Ordinary women fear bodies.
النساء العاديات يخشين الأجساد.
Why do you show no fear,
لماذا لا تُظهر أي خوف؟
but checked her body?
لكن هل فحص جسدها؟
I happen to know medicine.
أنا أعرف الطب.
You must be remarkable at it.
لا بد أنك بارع في ذلك.
You even know by injecting mercury,
بل إنك تعرف ذلك عن طريق حقن الزئبق،
you can get a complete human skin.
يمكنك الحصول على جلد بشري كامل.
I happened to pass by the palace last night.
مررت بالصدفة بالقصر الليلة الماضية.
Did you
هل أنت
see who killed her?
هل رأيتم من قتلها؟
You killed her, did you?
أنت قتلتها، أليس كذلك؟
I didn't kill anyone!
لم أقتل أحداً!
It wasn't me!
لم أكن أنا!
Then how would you know
إذن كيف ستعرف؟
such a vicious method of harming people?
هل هذه طريقة شريرة لإيذاء الناس؟
It's like a poison maker
إنه أشبه بصانع سموم
who knows how to make medicine.
من يعرف كيف يصنع الدواء.
Convicting me of murder based on a single sentence
إدانتي بالقتل بناءً على جملة واحدة
would be far too rash.
سيكون ذلك متهوراً للغاية.
I was speaking casually.
كنت أتحدث بشكل عفوي.
Then watch your words and deeds.
ثم انتبه لأقوالك وأفعالك.
If nothing else, I'll take my leave.
على الأقل، سأغادر.
(Zhen'er, you never failed)
(زين إير، لم تفشلي أبداً)
(to surprise me.)
(لتفاجئني.)
The area has been searched once.
تم تفتيش المنطقة مرة واحدة.
Apart from your golden hairpin,
وبغض النظر عن دبوس شعرك الذهبي،
nothing else was found.
لم يتم العثور على أي شيء آخر.
Could I really have killed Consort Xi?
هل يُعقل أنني قتلت القرينة شي؟
Impossible!
مستحيل!
Worried?
قلق؟
In this era,
في هذا العصر،
the imperial physicians, with the highest medical authority,
الأطباء الإمبراطوريون، الذين يتمتعون بأعلى سلطة طبية،
can't even stitch a piece of human skin perfectly,
لا يستطيع حتى خياطة قطعة من جلد الإنسان بشكل مثالي،
let alone
ناهيك عن
flaying off a complete human skin.
سلخ جلد بشري كامل.
I studied anatomy.
لقد درست علم التشريح.
I can extract a complete spinal cord from a rat,
أستطيع استخراج الحبل الشوكي بالكامل من فأر،
so I can flay a complete human skin.
حتى أتمكن من سلخ جلد إنسان كامل.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
If I did kill someone,
لو أنني قتلت شخصاً ما،
what would you do?
ماذا ستفعل؟
I'll act impartially.
سأتصرف بنزاهة.
You'll kill me?
هل ستقتلني؟
I don't want to,
لا أريد ذلك،
unless you can prove yourself.
إلا إذا استطعت إثبات نفسك.
After all, I'm just a puppet.
في النهاية، أنا مجرد دمية.
Lu Zhen'er,
لو زينير،
I questioned that palace maid
استجوبت خادمة القصر تلك
when she wasn't that mad.
عندما لم تكن غاضبة إلى هذا الحد.
She said she saw you got physical with Consort Xi.
قالت إنها رأتك تتشاجر مع القرينة شي.
I did, but I was just trying to scare her.
نعم، فعلت ذلك، لكنني كنت أحاول فقط تخويفها.
I threatened her
لقد هددتها
and then let her go.
ثم دعها تذهب.
She said she saw you flay the skin with her own eyes.
قالت إنها رأتك وأنت تسلخ الجلد بأم عينيها.
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
I didn't kill anyone!
لم أقتل أحداً!
I'll go look for more evidence.
سأبحث عن المزيد من الأدلة.
(Empress Regnant's Legend)
(أسطورة الإمبراطورة الحاكمة)
This book looks so modern.
هذا الكتاب يبدو عصرياً للغاية.
(Episode 1: The Sorceress Rises)
(الحلقة 1: صعود الساحرة)
(Best Fortune)
(أفضل حظ)
The best fortune.
أفضل حظ.
This person looks so much like me.
هذا الشخص يشبهني كثيراً.
Make an incision here and pour mercury in.
قم بعمل شق هنا واسكب الزئبق فيه.
Then I'll get a complete human skin.
ثم سأحصل على جلد بشري كامل.
Your Highness, would you like to give it a try?
صاحب السمو، هل ترغب في تجربته؟
(So,)
(لذا،)
(I did all of this?)
(هل فعلت كل هذا؟)
Turns out,
اتضح،
I'm just a cardboard character
أنا مجرد شخصية كرتونية
from a comic book.
من كتاب مصور.
♪Spring comes late after the snow♪
♪يأتي الربيع متأخراً بعد الثلج♪
♪Having endured sorrow and joy♪
♪بعد أن تحملنا الحزن والفرح♪
♪Wandering the streets, the story unfinished♪
♪أتجول في الشوارع، والقصة لم تكتمل♪
♪Turning around, I lost you♪
♪استدرت، ففقدتك♪
♪Separated by the dust of the past♪
♪يفصل بينهما غبار الماضي♪
♪Our reunion veiled by moonlight♪
♪لقاءنا محجوب بضوء القمر♪
♪Grant me indifference or tenderness♪
♪امنحني اللامبالاة أو الحنان♪
♪Crowds push past, brushing shoulders♪
♪تتدافع الحشود، وتتلامس الأكتاف♪
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
♪ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح♪
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
♪الشوق ينسج في شبكة♪
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
♪لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر♪
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى نظرتك♪
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
♪الزمن، يترك وراءه الكثير من الماضي♪
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
♪يتبع الخراب البهاء♪
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
♪فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا♪
♪Will I kiss your face♪
♪هل سأقبل وجهك؟♪
♪Never forgotten, hope you've been well♪
لن ننساك أبدًا، أتمنى أن تكون بخير
♪Borrowing the first ray of spring light♪
♪استعارة أول شعاع من ضوء الربيع♪
♪Can it bring about for us?♪
♪هل يمكن أن يحقق لنا ذلك؟♪
♪One look back, lasting till the end of time♪
♪نظرة واحدة إلى الوراء، تدوم إلى نهاية الزمان♪
♪Love grows wild within the soul♪
♪ينمو الحبّ بعنفٍ في أعماق الروح♪
♪Longing weaves into a net♪
♪الشوق ينسج في شبكة♪
♪Dare not speak, dare not gaze♪
♪لا تجرؤ على الكلام، لا تجرؤ على النظر♪
♪Yet I crave your glance♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى نظرتك♪
♪Time, leaving many pasts behind♪
♪الزمن، يترك وراءه الكثير من الماضي♪
♪Desolation follows splendor♪
♪يتبع الخراب البهاء♪
♪Only after seeing enough worldly absurdity♪
♪فقط بعد رؤية ما يكفي من سخافات الدنيا♪
♪Will I kiss your face♪
♪هل سأقبل وجهك؟♪